<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>software on Alexander Symons&#39;s Portfolio</title>
    <link>http://FlyingFish800.github.io/tags/software/</link>
    <description>Recent content in software on Alexander Symons&#39;s Portfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2023 21:12:17 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://FlyingFish800.github.io/tags/software/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Chip 8</title>
      <link>http://FlyingFish800.github.io/emulators/chip_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2023 21:12:17 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://FlyingFish800.github.io/emulators/chip_8/</guid>
      <description>Link to the my Chip 8 toolchain repository: https://github.com/FlyingFish800/Chip-8-Interpreter-Java
Back in 2021 I discovered the Chip 8 instruction set from a video on youtube of someone writing their own interpreter for it. It looked like a really cool project to spend some on my extra quarentine freetime on, so I went to the technical reference they used and started to work on my own interpreter.
Chip 8 is a great first introduction to computer systems and architecture, especially if you go down the route of writing your own interpreter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homebrew CPU Emulator</title>
      <link>http://FlyingFish800.github.io/emulators/homebrew_cpu/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2023 10:55:12 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://FlyingFish800.github.io/emulators/homebrew_cpu/</guid>
      <description>Link to my UMI 8 toolchain repository: https://github.com/FlyingFish800/UMI8
After watching videos by Ben Eater and SLU-4 on their custom 8-bit CPUs implemented in 7400 series TTL logic chips, I became interested in CPU architecture design and decided to make my own. I started with designing the archecture and instruction set, and I set the following goals in mind:
 The hardware should be as simple as possible It must be achievable with TTL Logic gates It should have stack/subroutine operations  My first revision of this architecture was a 16 bit design using a full 16 bit data bus, a write only memory offset register to hack in a virtual address space, and a similarly hacky interrupt system.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
